Register of the John K. Emmerson Papers, 1931-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
John K. Emmerson Papers
1931-1985
80115
Hoover Institution Archives
83 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 2 envelopes (37.5 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Japanese-American relations, post-World War II Japanese politics, the Vietnamese War, and U.S. foreign policy in the Far East. Papers date mainly from the period of Emmerson's retirement.
Emmerson, John K., 1908-1984.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1908, March 17 Born, Canon City, Colorado
1929 B.A., Colorado College
1930 M.A., New York University
1930-1931 Teacher of social science, University of Nebraska
1934 Married Dorothy McLaughlin
1935-1941 Foreign Service Officer, Japan
1943-1945 Political Adviser to General Joseph Stilwell, China-Burma-India Theater
1944 American emissary to Chinese Communists in Yenan
1945 Political Adviser to General Douglas MacArthur
1952-1955 Counselor, Deputy Chief of Mission, Karachi, Pakistan
1955-1957 Counselor, Deputy Chief of Mission, Beirut, Lebanon
1957-1958 Political Counselor, Paris
1958-1962 Consul General, Lagos, Nigeria; Salisbury, Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland
1962-1966 Counselor Minister and Deputy Chief of Mission, Japan
1966-1967 State Department Diplomat in Residence, Stanford University
1968 Retired from the Foreign Service
1968-1984 Senior research fellow, Hoover Institution and research associate, Northeast Asia-U.S. Policy Forum, Stanford University
1971 Author, Arms, Yen and Power: The Japanese Dilemma
1973 Co-author, with Leonard A. Humphreys, Will Japan Rearm?
1978 Author, The Japanese Thread: A Life in the U.S. Foreign Service
1979 Author, A View From Yenan
1984, March 24 Died, Palo Alto, California
United States. Dept. of State.; Diplomats--United States.; East Asia--Foreign relations--United States.; East Asia.; Japan--Foreign relations--United States.; Japan--Politics and government--1945-; Japan.; United States--Foreign relations--East Asia.; United States--Foreign relations--Japan.; United States--Foreign relations.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.
- Biographical File, 1966-1982.
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketches, records, memoranda, certificates, correspondence, and clippings related to the career of John K. Emmerson, arranged by physical form.
- Correspondence, 1965-1983.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- Speeches And Writings, 1947-1984.
  Manuscripts, notes, drafts, correspondence, printed articles, reviews, research materials, arranged chronologically.
- Subject File, 1937-1984.
  Correspondence, memoranda, printed material, reports, charts, arranged alphabetically by topic.
- Audio-Visual.
  General note
  See photo card catalog
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1966-1982
  - Address lists, appointments, calling cards (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards (Folder 2)
  - Biographical data (Folder 3)
  - Certificates (Folder 4)
  - Clippings (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence related to Emmerson's Freedom of Information-Privacy Acts inquiries (Folder 6)
  - Correspondence related to Emmerson's nomination as Ambassador to Tanganyika (Folder 7)
  - Education. Colorado College. Correspondence, class reunion materials (Folder 8)
  - Employment (Folder 9-10)
  - Invitations, guest lists (Folder 11)
  - Itineraries, travel schedules (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellany (Folder 2)
  - Programs (Folder 3)
  - Resignation and retirement (Folder 4)
  - Travel in U.S.S.R. (Folder 5)
  - Visa application form (Folder 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1965-1983
  - General (Box 2)
    - Undated (Folder 7)
    - 1965 (Folder 8)
    - 1966 (Folder 9)
    - 1967 (Folder 10)
    - 1968 (Folder 11)
    - 1969 (Folder 12)
    - 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1971 (Folder 2)
    - 1972 (Folder 3)
    - 1973 (Folder 4)
    - 1974 (Folder 5)
    - 1975 (Folder 6)
    - 1976 (Folder 7)
    - 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Folder 2)
    - 1979 (Folder 3)
    - 1980 (Folder 4)
    - 1981 (Folder 5)
    - 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1983 (Folder 2)
  - Abrahams, William M., 1978-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Ariyoshi, Koji, 1971-1972 (Folder 4)
  - Asia Society, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - Asian Institute for Public Policy, 1975-1977 (Folder 6)
  - Axelbank, Albert, 1973-1976 (Folder 7)
  - Baker, James, 1973 (Folder 8)
  - Barber, Willard, 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Barnett, Robert W., 1968-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Befu, Harumi, 1978 (Folder 11)
  - Behrens, Bernice, 1979 (Folder 12)
  - Bohlen, Mrs. Charles E., 1974 (Folder 13)
  - Borg, Dorothy, 1968 (Folder 14)
  - Borton, Hugh, 1975 (Folder 15)
  - Boyce, Richard Fyfe, 1971-1980 (Folder 16)
  - Briggs, Norman, 1980-1981 (Folder 17)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1967 (Folder 18)
  - Bundy, William P., 1967-1973 (Folder 19)
  - Busk, Douglas, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Chao, Dan, 1973-1974 (Folder 2)
  - Chinese People's Association for Friendship With Foreign Countries, 1978-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Clark, Harlan B., 1967 (Folder 4)
  - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1975-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Colorado College, 1967-1972 (Folder 6)
  - Communist Party of Japan, 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Consulate General of Japan, San Francisco, 1969-1983 (Folder 8)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1967-1978 (Folder 9)
  - Crockett, William J., 1965-1966 (Folder 10)
  - Cronkite, Walter, 1967-1981 (Folder 11)
  - Crowe, Philip K., 1969-1976 (Folder 12)
  - Davies, John Paton, 1970-1978 (Folder 13)
  - Dingman, Roger, 1974-1979 (Folder 14)
  - Domke, Mrs. Paul, 1979-1983 (Folder 15)
  - Enoki, Masumichi, 1969 (Folder 16)
  - Eveland, Wilbur C., 1978-1980 (Folder 17)
  - Fairbank, John K., 1977-1978 (Folder 18)
  - Fearey, Robert A., 1968-1980 (Folder 19)
  - Foreign Service Journal, 1976-1979 (Folder 20)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1966-1973 (Folder 21)
  - Foreign Service Research, Inc., 1969 (Folder 22)
  - Freeman, Fulton, 1968 (Folder 23)
  - Galbraith, Francis J., 1967-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Georgetown University, School of Foreign Service, 1979-1981 (Folder 2)
  - Glei, William F., 1978-1982 (Folder 3)
  - Green, Marshall, 1972 (Folder 4)
  - Gretton, Peter, 1974-1980 (Folder 5)
  - Habib, Philip, 1972-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Halloran, Richard, 1979-1980 (Folder 7)
  - Harding, Harry, 1980 (Folder 8)
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Holland, Harrison, 1972-1982 (Folder 10)
  - Holloway, J.K., Jr., 1979 (Folder 11)
  - Holt, Pat M., 1975 (Folder 12)
  - Huang Hua, 1973 (Folder 13)
  - Huntley, James R., 1974 (Folder 14)
  - Immerman, Robert M., 1971-1983 (Folder 15)
  - Iriye, Akira, 1973-1982 (Folder 16)
  - Ishikawa, Daisuke, 1975-1980 (Folder 17)
  - Japan Defense Agency, 1965-1969 (Folder 18)
  - Japan Society, 1970-1982 (Folder 19)
  - Japan Times, 1969 (Folder 20)
  - Japan Trade Center, 1980-1983 (Folder 21)
  - Jessup, Philip C., 1971-1972 (Folder 22)
  - Jiji Press, 1969-1978 (Folder 23)
  - Johnson, Chalmers, 1972-1979 (Folder 24)
  - Johnson, U. Alexis, 1966-1982 (Folder 25)
  - KQED, Inc., 1977-1978 (Folder 26)
  - Kahn, E.J., Jr., 1973-1978 (Folder 27)
  - Kajima Institute of International Peace, 1973 (Folder 28)
  - Kennedy, Edward M., 1965 (Folder 29)
  - Kerr, George, 1971-1980 (Folder 30)
  - Kirkwood, Robert C., 1969 (Folder 31)
  - Kotani, Etsuo, 1971-1978 (Folder 32)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1976 (Folder 33)
  - Lincoln, Robert A., 1974 (Folder 34)
  - Macalester College, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Mansfield, Mike, 1980 (Folder 2)
  - Marker, Jamsheed, 1979 (Folder 3)
  - McConaughy, Walter P., 1969-1972 (Folder 4)
  - McLaughlin, Glenn (?), 1981 (Folder 5)
  - Meloy, Francis E., Jr., 1969 (Folder 6)
  - Meyer, Armin H., 1969 (Folder 7)
  - Min Kwan-shik, 1975-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Mlynarchik, Roy A., 1968-1981 (Folder 9)
  - Morris, Brewster, 1966-1978 (Folder 10)
  - Nakasone, Yasuhiro, 1979 (Folder 11)
  - National Archives and Records Services, 1975 (Folder 12)
  - Nelson, Clifford, 1977 (Folder 13)
  - Newman, Robert P., 1981 (Folder 14)
  - Nosaka, Sanzo, 1973 (Folder 15)
  - Novak, Michael, 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Oberdorfer, Don, 1980 (Folder 17)
  - Ogawa, Heishiro, 1979 (Folder 18)
  - Ohira, Mrs. Masayoshi, 1980 (Folder 19)
  - Okimoto, Dan, 1979 (Folder 20)
  - Onoe, Kazuo, 1971-1980 (Folder 21)
  - Osborn, David, 1970 (Folder 22)
  - Owen, Dwight, 1967-1969 (Folder 23)
  - Packard, George, 1968-1980 (Folder 24)
  - Patino, Washington, 1976-1981 (Folder 25)
  - Peterkin, Wilbur, 1978-1979 (Folder 26)
  - Petree, Richard, 1972-1976 (Folder 27)
  - Reader's Digest, 1968-1971 (Folder 28)
  - Reischauer, Edwin O., 1969-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Riddleberger, James W., 1968 (Folder 2)
  - Roy, Stapleton, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1968-1977 (Folder 4)
  - Salisbury, Harrison, 1971-1979 (Folder 5)
  - Sato, Seizaburo, 1974 (Folder 6)
  - Scalapino, Robert A., 1977-1978 (Folder 7)
  - Schodt, Eddie W., 1967-1974 (Folder 8)
  - Scott, John, 1971 (Folder 9)
  - Sebald, William J., 1967-1968 (Folder 10)
  - Service, John S., 1977-1979 (Folder 11)
  - Shaw, William, 1974-1976 (Folder 12)
  - Shimanouchi, Toshiro, 1973-1982 (Folder 13)
  - Shoesmith, Thomas P., 1967-1982 (Folder 14)
  - Sinden, Alfred and Theodora, 1978-1981 (Folder 15)
  - Sneider, Richard L., 1967-1976 (Folder 16)
  - Spinks, Charles Nelson, 1976-1977 (Folder 17)
  - Steeves, John M., 1968-1978 (Folder 18)
  - Sullivan, William H., 1972 (Folder 19)
  - Sutton, Gerald M., 1971 (Folder 20)
  - Swearingen, Rodger, 1970-1978 (Folder 21)
  - Symington, Stuart, 1972-1975 (Folder 22)
  - Tamba, Theodore, 1972 (Folder 23)
  - Time, Inc., 1967-1978 (Folder 24)
  - Toland, John, 1970 (Folder 25)
  - Treat, Payson, 1967-1969 (Folder 26)
  - Trezise, Philip H., 1970 (Folder 27)
  - Underhill, Francis T., 1969-1981 (Folder 28)
  - Vaccari, Oreste, 1968 (Folder 29)
  - Wakaizumi, Kei, 1967-1969 (Folder 30)
  - Ward, Robert E., 1968 (Folder 31)
  - Woodward, Richard J., 1976 (Folder 32)
  - Wray, Harry, 1981 (Folder 33)
  - Yasukawa, Takeshi, 1974-1975 (Folder 34)
  - Yomiuri Shimbun, 1969 (Folder 35)
  - Yost, Charles W., 1970-1978 (Folder 36)
  - Zurhellen, J. Owen, Jr., 1967-1975 (Folder 37)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1947-1984
  - Speaking engagements. Correspondence, l967-l983 (Box 10, Folder 1-10)
  - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Acculturation Process of Genus Correspondenti in the Mass-Komi Milieu and the Concatenacious Impact of the Foreign Policy Syndrome as Practiced by the Typus Diplomaticus", poem (Folder 2)
  - "The Future of U.S.-Japan Relations", Outline, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Review of Gunboat Diplomacy by James Cable, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "Is Japan Changing?",. News Broadcast (NBC), February 22, 1947 (Folder 5)
  - "The Foreign Service and Foreign Policy", Lecture notes and research materials, l967. (Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes on Japan and U.S. Relations, ca. 1967 (Folder 7-8)
  - List of public speaking engagements, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes, l969 (Folder 10)
  - "Japan: An Eye on 1970", Foreign Affairs, January, 1969 (Folder 11)
  - "Japan and U.S. Security", speech, Industrial College of the Armed Forces, January 7, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "The Security of Japan", March 15, 1969 (Folder 2)
  - "Japan and Disarmament and Arms Control", April 26, 1969 (Folder 3)
  - "China Makes U.S. Look at Japan and Taiwan", ca. 1970 (Folder 4)
  - "Japan's Future Role in Pacific Asia", ca. 1970 (Folder 5)
  - "Self Defense Forces and Japan's Role in Asia", outlines, ca. 1970 (Folder 6)
  - Review of Japanese Recognition of the U.S.S.R. by George A. Lensen, ca. 1970 (Folder 7)
  - Arms, Yen and Power: The Japanese Dilemma, 1971
    - Advertisements (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence (Folder 9-10)
    - Distribution list (Folder 11)
    - Introduction to Japanese edition (Folder 12)
    - Outlines (Folder 13)
    - Publishers (Folder 14-15)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous drafts, 1971 (Folder 2)
  - "Japan", Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, 1971 (Folder 3)
  - Drafts and research materials on the Japanese Communist Party, 1971 (Folder 4)
  - "China-Japan's Role", New York Times, April 24, 1971 (Folder 5)
  - "Asian States", panel discussion, U.S. Army War College, November 29, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - "Ending of the War", Outline, ca. 1972. (Folder 7)
  - "Japan", Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Review of Japanese Foreign Policy on the Eve of the Pacific War. A Soviet View. by Leonid N. Kutakov and The Strange Neutrality, Soviet-Japanese Relations During the Second World War, 1941-1945 by George Alexander Lensen, 1972 (Folder 9)
  - "Troubles Ahead for Okinawa", New York Times, March 9, 1972 (Folder 10)
  - "The Balance of Power in Asia After the Nixon China Visit", Sekai Shuho, April 18, 1972 (Folder 11)
  - "The Japanese Communist Party After 50 Years", Asian Survey, July, 1972 (Folder 12)
  - "The United States and Japan: Uneasy Partners", Pacific Community, July, 1972 (Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Japan: The Limits of Power", galleys and drafts, 1973 (Folder 2)
  - "Japan", Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, 1973 (Folder 3)
  - "Japan's Next Turning Point", ca. 1973 (Folder 4)
  - "New U.S. Policy Towards East Asia", ca. 1973 (Folder 5)
  - Will Japan Rearm? A Study in Attitudes, Co-authored by Leonard A. Humphreys, 1973. (Folder 6)
  - "Defense, Treaties and the Nuclear Umbrella", January, 1973 (Folder 7)
  - "Much Gets Done At Parties", Palo Alto Times, March 22, 1973 (Folder 8)
  - "Japanese and Americans in Peru: 1942-1943", Foreign Service Journal, May, 1973 (Folder 9)
  - "Japanese and Americans In a New World in a New Age", September l, 1973 (Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1974 (Folder 11)
  - Notes on Japan, 1974 (Folder 12)
  - "Japan", Yearbook on International Communist Affairs, 1974 (Folder 13)
  - "Now...A New role for the U.S.-Japan Partnership", 1974 (Folder 14)
  - Review of Japan's Foreign Policy by Frank C. Langdon, The American Political Science Review, 1974 (Folder 15)
  - Speech notes, 1974 (Folder 16)
  - "Arms Are Not Japan's Answer", January, 1974 (Folder 17)
  - "Interaction of the Four Powers in Northeast Asia", speech, Defense College, Tokyo, Japan, October, 1974 (Folder 18)
  - Notes and research materials on Japan, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - "Japanese and Americans in a New World in a New Age", revised, 1975 (Folder 2)
  - Speech notes, 1975 (Folder 3)
  - "American Foreign Policy in Asia After Vietnam", April 30, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - "A Post-Vietnam Look at U.S.-Japan Relations", June, 1975 (Folder 5)
  - Review of East Asia and U.S. Security by Ralph Clough, Political Science Quarterly, July, 1975 (Folder 6)
  - "After 30 Years: Japan and America", speech, Osaka, Japan, September, 1975 (Folder 7)
  - "Independent 'Democratic' Communism", December, 1975 (Folder 8)
  - "Japan Today", speech, December 16, 1975 and January 7, 1976 (Folder 9)
  - Review of Asia's New Giant: How the Japanese Economy Works, edited by Hugh Patrick and Henry Rosovsky, 1976 (Folder 10)
  - Speech notes, 1976 (Folder 11)
  - "Italy, France, Japan -- Where Will It All End?", New York Times, January 8, 1976 (Folder 12)
  - "Will Japan Rearm?", speech notes, February 24, 1976 (Folder 13)
  - "U.S.-Japan", speech notes, November 10, 1976 (Folder 14)
  - Review of The Origins of the Cold War in Asia, edited by Yonusuke Nagai, Akira Iriye, 1977 (Folder 15)
  - "Taiwan 1939", The Asia Mail, April, 1977 (Folder 16)
  - "Letter From Japan", Foreign Service Journal, September 9, 1977 (Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes, l978 (Folder 18)
  - The Japanese Thread: A Life in the U.S. Foreign Service, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence (Folder 1-5)
    - Distribution lists (Folder 6)
    - Drafts, synopsis, booklist (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Financial records (Folder 2)
    - Publisher (Folder 3-5)
    - Reviews (Folder 6-8)
  - "Principles vs. Realities", ca. 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Review of Valley of Darkness, The Japanese People and World War II by Thomas R.H. Havens, Foreign Service Journal, 1978 (Folder 2)
  - Review of "Cultural Relations and China Policy, 1942-1945", Pacific Historical Review, January, 1978 (Folder 3)
  - Review of The Origins of the Cold War in Asia by Akira Iriye, International Journal, January, 1978 (Folder 4)
  - Review of Japanese International Negotiating Style by Michael Blaker, Political Science Quarterly, February 24, 1978 (Folder 5)
  - "Japanese Political Parties in Transition, The Japanese Communist Party", speech, Association for Asian Studies, March 31-April 2, 1978 (Folder 6)
  - "U.S.-Japan Relations 1978", speech, Hakone Conference, July, 1978 (Folder 7)
  - "Concepts of Asia: From Tokyo and Washington", Asia Pacific Community, October, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Interview for Mainichi, October 14, 1978 (Folder 9)
  - "A View from Yenan", 1 printed copy, 1979. (Folder 10)
  - "War With Japan Might Have Ended Sooner", Draft and typescript, 1979. (Folder 11)
  - "China: After 35 Years", Foreign Service Journal, March, 1979 (Folder 12)
  - "America's Expertise on Japan", June 29, 1979 (Folder 13)
  - Draft outline on Japan, July 30, 1979 (Folder 14)
  - "Stand Firm, U.S.",. A reply to Yukio Matsuyama, November 24, 1979 (Folder 15)
  - "The Birth of Japan's Postwar Political Parties", 1980 (Folder 16)
  - Foreword for Japan: 1948-1954 by Betsy O'Hara, 1980 (Folder 17)
  - "The Security Environment in Northeast Asia",. Draft, notes, paper, January 17, 1980 (Folder 18)
  - "Japan in U.S. Foreign Policy", paper presented to International Studies Association, March 1980 (Folder 19)
  - "Our Asian Interests: Japanese Allies, Chinese Friends", speech, Commonwealth Club, May 30, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - "Keep the Japan Security Treaty As Is", Wall Street Journal, April 1, 1982 (Folder 2)
  - "Myths and Realities of Japanese-American Relations", Hokubei Mainichi, April 21, 1982 (Folder 3)
  - "Japan and America in the World", June, 1982 (Folder 4)
  - Review of Coping With U.S.-Japanese Trade Conflicts, edited by I.M. Destler and Hideo Sato, Political Science Quarterly, July, 1982 (Folder 5)
  - "U.S.-Japan Defense Agreements Transcend Economy and Culture", New York News World, July 9, 1982 (Folder 6)
  - "World Commerce and Defense: U.S., Japan Strive for Mutual Awareness", Daily News, July 10, 1982 (Folder 7)
  - "U.S., Japan: Beyond Trade", Fresno Bee, July 12, 1982 (Folder 8)
  - Lecture, Foothill College, July 22, 1982 (Folder 9)
  - Untitled excerpt from article, originally written for Journal of International Studies, (Summer, 1982) 1983 (Folder 10)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1937-1984
  - American Assembly. Correspondence, agenda, lists of participants, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - American Ditchley Foundation. Correspondence, brochures, conference reports, biographical data on conference participants, 1968, 1980 (Folder 12)
  - American Historical Association. Correspondence, notes, program for annual meeting, December 28-30, 1974 (Folder 13)
  - American-Soviet Conference on Asia. Correspondence, notes, map, list of conference participants, program, paper, 1977 (Folder 14)
  - Asia. Bibliography, Japanese press summaries from the American Embassy in Japan, 1969-1976 (Folder 15)
  - Asia Foundation. Correspondence, resume, 1977-1981 (Folder 16)
  - Asia Society. Program, participant list, 1975 (Folder 17)
  - Asian Studies on the Pacific Coast. Correspondence, conference brochures, list of conference participants, travel documents, memoranda, 1971 (Folder 18)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies. Correspondence, brochures, programs, lists of conference participants, applications (Box 20)
    - 1970 (Folder 1)
    - 1971 (Folder 2)
    - 1972 (Folder 3)
    - 1973 (Folder 4)
    - 1974 (Folder 5)
    - 1975-1976 (Folder 6)
    - 1977-1979 (Folder 7)
  - Association for Asian Studies. Correspondence, newsletter, summary of proceedings, report, working drafts, membership lists, 1969-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
  - Atlantic Council. Correspondence, memoranda, working drafts, notes, papers, outlines
    - 1979 (Folder 4)
    - 1980 (Folder 5-7)
    - 1981 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1982 (Folder 2-6)
    - 1983 (Folder 7)
  - Atlantic Institute for International Affairs. Printed material, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Australia. Background notes, U.S. Department of State, 1966 (Folder 2)
  - Battelle Seminar and Study Program. Correspondence, working drafts and papers, questionnaire, brochure, progress report, memoranda, 1975-1981 (Folder 3-5)
  - Canadian Institute of International Affairs. Correspondence, meeting minutes, list of conference participants, printed materials, miscellany, 1968-1970 (Folder 6)
  - Chapman College. Correspondence, printed materials, 1973-1974 (Folder 7)
  - China
    - General
      - Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Folder 8)
      - Notes, 1974-1976 (Folder 9)
      - Printed materials, 1973-1976 (Folder 10)
    - Chang Chih Chun, 1944 (Folder 11)
    - History (Box 24)
      - Background papers for panel on the Cultural Revolution and China's foreign policy, 1966 (Folder 1)
      - "China: The First Year Without Mao" by Harry Harding, October, 1977 (Folder 2)
    - Literature. "Drum Ballad of the Chinese Guerilla Leader, Miao Ke-hsiu" by Chih Chung, 1937 (Folder 3)
    - Travel. Trip to the People's Republic of China by Yung Su Tsai, January l to January 26, 1980 (Folder 4)
  - Council on Foreign Relations. Correspondence, membership list, memoranda, conference participants, printed material, 1969-1981 (Folder 5)
  - DACOR Educational and Welfare Foundation. Correspondence, printed material, notes, fellowship applications, 1977-1981 (Folder 6)
  - Energy. Draft outline, "International Aspects of Energy Policy", November 9, 1972 (Folder 7)
  - Fellowship Forum. Correspondence, membership list, printed material, articles of incorporation, 1983-1984 (Folder 8)
  - Financial Research and Systems (FRS). Correspondence, memoranda, working paper, 1973-1974 (Folder 9)
  - Hong Kong. Background notes, U.S. Department of State, 1966 (Folder 10)
  - Indonesia. Background notes, U.S. Department of State, 1967 (Folder 11)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis. Correspondence, security questionnaire, current projects list, 1968-1973 (Folder 12)
  - Institute for U.S.-Japan Relations. Correspondence, printed material, 1981 (Folder 13)
  - International Congress of Orientalists. Correspondence, printed material, membership list, 1972-1974 (Folder 14)
  - International Cultural Exchange Foundation. Correspondence, general information data, course outline, reading list, 1974 (Folder 15)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board. Correspondence, memoranda, personal recommendation, curriculum vitae, trip report by Emmerson,"Visit to the Soviet Union", October 21 -November 4, 1974, 1974-1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - International Study Project. Correspondence, research materials, memoranda, 1970-1971 (Folder 2)
  - Japan
    - General. Printed material, 1970-1984 (Folder 3-5)
    - Agriculture. Japanese press summaries, 1977 (Folder 6)